# Steven Hocking

46 Longford Road, Reddish, Stockport, SK5 6UX.

0750 345 6222 steve@codemunki.es

http://www.codemunki.es/ http://stackoverflow.com/story/stevehocking https://github.com/steve-codemunkies

## Profile

I am a passionate, highly engaged technical architect/principal software engineer, with a focus on delivering high quality software first time, every time. I have extensive experience working in organisations of differing size and maturity in their experience of delivering software.

I am currently working across several teams, assisting with the imminent delivery of systems to a new customer.

My leadership style is to facilitate the members of my team in solving the issues placed before them, whilst providing technical guidance. I feel that success is best achieved by engaging every member of a team, and the best way to do this is to show, not tell.

# **Technical Experience**

- Microsoft SQL Server 20 Years
- C# / .NET Framework 15 Years+
- Test Driven Development 8 Years+
- ASP.NET MVC 7 Years
- PowerShell 7 Years+
- WCF Services 6 Years+
- RabbitMq 4 Years+
- TopShelf (windows services) 4 Years+
- Continuous Integration (Jenkins) and Automated Deployment (Octopus) 3 Years
- Modern JavaScript (Durandal/Angular/Karma/Jasmine) 3 Years
- SQL Server/Windows Server Maintenance 3 Years+
- .NET Core 3 Years +
- NoSQL (MongoDb) 2 Years+
- Docker/Kubernetes 12 Months+
- Rancher 9 Months+
- TeamCity 9 Months+
- Event Sourcing and EventStore 9 Months+

## Technical Architecture Experience

- On the Beach 2015-December 2018
- IVendi January 2019 September 2019

#### Team Management Experience

- iVendi 2019 Directorate Technical Lead, providing technical leadership for two teams
- On The Beach 2015-2018 initially 3 developers, currently 2 senior software engineers, 4 software engineers, 2 junior software engineers, 1 business analyst, 1 product owner
- Swinton 2012-2013 4 developers and one tester
- Intechnica 2010-2011 initially 2 developers and one tester, finally 4 developers and one tester
- PwC 2007-2010 multiple teams, from 2 developer-5 developers, also including testers and business analysts

### Other Work Related Experience

• 5th March, 2019 – DNN Lightning Talks – An Introduction to Event Sourcing – http://bit.ly/dnn-sh-es

## Work History

- iVendi ltd, Salford Quays Principal Developer/Directorate Technical Lead March 2019-Onwards
  - Providing technical leadership to two teams

0

- O Working with teams and the business to formulate and agree KPIs
- Mentoring team leads to help them get the best from their teams and achieve the results required by the business
- Continue to assist teams outside of my directorate to deliver key software for new client
- Assisting team leads by providing back-up mentoring for new North Coders graduates
- iVendi ltd, Salford Quays Principal Developer January 2019-March 2019
  - Assisting multiple teams to deliver key software for new client
  - Mentoring new North Coders graduate
- On The Beach Group plc, Cheadle Senior .NET Developer/Team Lead Principal Software Engineer (.NET) (Lead) – January 2016-December 2018
  - My team was responsible for the Beds system (used to manage room bookings and contracts) and the Transfers system (used to manage airport transfer bookings and contracts) which between them process bookings covering ~70% of the business revenues
  - I helped move the team from infrequent deliveries of medium size with moderate quality to frequent deliveries of small, high quality changes; this has been achieved by:
    - using TDD, CI (Jenkins) and Automated Deployments (Octopus Deployment)
    - additionally my team DevOps the systems the applications run on
  - I worked with my team to architect and direct the creation of new tools to allow users to administer aspects of systems that previously required development intervention
  - o The Beds and Transfers systems (both Webforms apps), were enhanced using:
    - WCF to build high performance/high availability core services
    - ASP.NET Core MVC/WebApi along with React.js to build management applications
    - TopShelf (with Quartz.net and/or RabbitMq) to provide background processing services
  - From January 2016-January 2018 I acted as Product Owner; January 2018-October 2018 I worked with the Head Product Owner and between October and December 2018 with a dedicated product owner to determine priorities, understand future business direction and at manage expectations.
  - I worked with the team to help them shape the Kanban-based agile processes the team used through regular retrospectives
- On The Beach Group plc, Cheadle .NET Developer October 2015-January 2016
- Sabbatical (following birth of second child) June 2015-October 2015
- Havas Health Software, Manchester Contract April 2014-June 2015 (renewed three times)
- Ukash/Smart Voucher Ltd, Cheshire Contract March 2013-March 2014 (renewed twice)
- Swinton Insurance Ltd, Manchester November 2011-March 2013
- Intechnica LLP, Manchester October 2010-November 2011
- 2Ergo Ltd, Salford Quays June 2010-September 2010
- PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) LLP, UK IT Design and Build (D&B), Manchester July 2004-June 2010
- Radius Computer Services Ltd, Altrincham September 1998-July 2004

#### Education

- Technical Specialist: Web Applications Development with Microsoft .NET Framework 4 (70-515) May 2011
- Microsoft Certified Application Developer June 2004
   Transcript viewable at <a href="https://mcp.microsoft.com/authenticate/validatemcp.aspx">https://mcp.microsoft.com/authenticate/validatemcp.aspx</a> (Transcript ID: 663027; Access code: 1976Sh0804).
- University of Central Lancashire BSc Software Engineering (Hons) 2:II July 1998
- University of Central Lancashire HND Software Engineering July 1996